舰长日志，星历3211.7
Captain's log, stardate 3211.7.
我们进入了伽马II星标准轨道
We are entering standard orbit about Gamma II,
这是一个有自动通讯系统的无人小行星
an uninhabited planetoid with an automatic communications
同时也是一个空间站
and astrogation station.
契科夫少尉，乌呼拉上尉和我
Ensign Chekov, Lieutenant Uhura and I
一起传送下去对空间站设备进行例行检查
will beam down and make a routine check of its facilities.
- 标准轨道，舰长 - 很好
- Standard orbit, captain. - Good.
- 史波克，留下看家 - 明白，舰长
- Mind the store, Mr. Spock. - Acknowledged, captain.
- 乌呼拉上尉，我们走 - 是，长官
- Lieutenant Uhura, let's go. - Yes, sir.
- 激活，史考特 - 是，舰长
- Energize, Scotty. - Aye, captain.
舰长，怎么回事？
Captain, what happened?
肯定是传送器失灵了
Must be a transporter malfunction.
简直是野蛮装卸啊
That was a rough trip.
这不是伽马II星
This isn't Gamma II.
看天空的颜色
Look at the colour of that sky.
我从来没见过这么粗暴的着陆方式
This is the craziest landing pad I've ever seen.
这儿有三元星
And that's a trinary sun.
- 斯考特呼叫舰桥 - 史波克
- Scott to Bridge. - Spock here.
史波克，舰长，乌呼拉上尉和契科夫
Mr. Spock, the captain, Lieutenant Uhura and Chekov,
他们消失了
they vanished.
他们上了传送台然后他们就消失了
They got onto the transporter platform and they just vanished.
斯考特，我假设你的意思是他们只是某种意义上的消失
I presume you mean they vanished in a manner not consistent
而并不是因为传送器的正常操作
with the usual workings of the transporter, Mr. Scott.
我就是这个意思
Why, of course I mean that.
他们要是被正常传送下去的我怎么会找你？
Do you think I'd call you if they just beamed down?
- 你检查操作了吗？ - 该检查的我都查了一遍
- Have you reversed controls? - I've made all the proper checks.
什么都没发生，传送灯都没亮！
There was nothing. There was no flash of light, nothing!
- 他们就消失了 - 能量波动？
- They were gone. - Power surge?
完全没显示，所有指数正常
Not down here. All the dials were right
传送机功能完全正常
and the transporter was functioning perfectly.
斯考特重新检查设备
Recheck your equipment, Mr. Scott.
我试试扫描星球看能不能找到他们，史波克
I'll scan for them on the planet's surface. Spock out.
但是舰长，如果我们不是在伽马II星，那么我们现在在哪儿？
But, captain, if we're not on Gamma II, then where are we?
这也是我想弄清楚的
That's what I'd like to know.
寇克呼叫进取号，寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise. Kirk to Enterprise.
信号中断
Dead.
- 我的也是 - 舰长，快看
- Mine too. - Captain, look.
相位枪调至击昏档位
Phasers on stun.
开火！
Fire!
进行肉搏
Hand-to-hand.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：诺阿诺阿、茶包泰迪
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第十六集
「三曲赌徒」
舰长日志，星历3211.8
Captain's log, stardate 3211.8.
在从进取号传送到伽马II星
While beaming down from the Enterprise
检查设备的过程中
to inspect facilities on Gamma II,
传送器的传送序列受到干扰
the normal transporter sequence has been interrupted
而我们被传送到了一个陌生的充满敌意的星球上
and we find ourselves on a strange and hostile planet,
被一群来自银河系各地的
surrounded by creatures belonging to races
生物包围了
scattered all through the galaxy.
非常精彩，寇克舰长
Excellent, Captain Kirk.
正如我们期待的那么充满力量并有进取精神
Although we expected strength and competitive spirit,
我们对此非常满意
we are greatly pleased.
大家都还好吗？
Either of you hurt?
我没事儿，舰长
I don't think so, captain.
没人受伤，舰长，目前为止
Nobody's hurt, captain. Yet.
令人钦佩，契科夫，令人钦佩
Admirable, Chekov, admirable.
你也是，乌呼拉
You also, Uhura.
你们的精神和舰长一样令人满意
Your spirit is as great as the captain's.
你们可以证明自己的价值
I can see you will all prove invaluable here.
我是高尔特，三曲星的奴隶主
I am Galt, master thrall of the planet Triskelion.
我是过来迎接你们的
I have been sent to welcome you.
这边走，舰长
There, captain.
现在你们准备接受训练
Now you are prepared for your training.
你怎么知道我们的名字的？
How do you know our names?
供应者非常期待你的到来，舰长
The Providers were expecting you, captain.
他们安排了你们的这次传送
They arranged your transportation.
- 你们的那些供应者，他们？ - 纠正，舰长
- These Providers of yours, are they..? - Correction, captain.
供应者不属于我们，我们是他们的从属
The Providers are not ours. We are theirs.
- 他们想从我这儿得到什么？ - 你们将被训练
- What do they want from us? - You are to be trained, of course.
奴隶在这儿还能有什么用处？
What other use is there for thralls?
奴隶？
Thralls?
你肯定是误会什么了
You must be mistaken.
我们是星际联邦的舰队军官，是来处理星际联邦事物的
We're officers of a United spaceship on Federation business.
不存在什么误会
There has been no mistake.
你们之前的那些职位在这儿都没用了，舰长
Your old titles mean nothing here, captain.
你们现在是奴隶
You are thralls now.
你们会被带到训练营
You are to be taken to the training enclosure.
走吧
Come,
那是专门为你们准备的地方
places have been prepared for you.
在获取到足够信息前我们哪儿也不去
We're not going anywhere until we have some information.
你是谁？这是哪儿？
Who are you? What is this place?
你打算怎么对待我么？
What do you think you'll do with us?
我是高尔特，奴隶主
I am Galt, the master thrall.
这里是三曲星
This place is the planet Triskelion.
送你们过来进行训练，你们将在此度过余生
You are to be trained and spend the rest of your lives here.
史波克，我已经把传送器从头到尾检查了一遍
Mr. Spock, I've checked that transporter from one end to the other.
每一个电子回路都工作正常
Every circuit works perfectly.
不管这次的能量波动是什么，肯定和传送器
Whatever that power surge was, it had nothing to do with the transporter
或船上的其他系统无关
or with any other system aboard this ship.
我已经开始相信这一结论了，斯考特
I'm beginning to believe that, Mr. Scott.
我已经对星球表面进行了两次扫描分析
I've conducted two sweeps of the planet's surface.
没有生命迹象
There is no sign of life.
那到底发生了什么？
Then what the devil is happening?
是说他们已经变成原子形态漂浮在宇宙中了吗？
Does that mean their atoms are just floating around out there?
不是，医生，即使他们变成了原子我们的扫描仪也能检测到
No, doctor. Even that would show up on our sensors.
那他们去哪儿了？
Where are they, then?
目前唯一的答案是，不知道
The only answers are negative. No magnetic storms,
没有磁暴，没有离子干扰，没有设备故障
no ionic interference, no breakdown in your equipment.
一问三不知对我们来说是不够的
A negative attitude is no good to us.
不管他们在哪儿，我们也不能就这么把他们扔在外面
We can't just leave them out there. Wherever they are.
我们会继续进行扫描的，医生
We shall continue sensor scans, doctor.
除了希望有一个合理解释外，现在我们只能这么做
At the moment, that is all we can do, except hope for a rational explanation.
希望？
Hope?
我一直以为这是人类才有的弱点，史波克
I always thought that was a human failing, Mr. Spock.
的确，医生
True, doctor.
近朱者赤近墨者黑
Constant exposure does result in a certain degree of contamination.
这是你们的舱室
These are your quarters.
开门，奴隶
Open, thralls.
这么做太愚蠢了，舰长
That was foolish, captain.
佩戴着驯服项圈
Escape is quite impossible,
你们根本不可能逃的掉
as demonstrated by your collars of obedience.
回到你们的舱室去
Return to your quarters.
他们不在这个太阳系的范围内
They're not within the confines of this solar system.
已经快一个小时了
It's been nearly an hour. Can people live that long
人类在被传送器分解成原子形式之后能活那么久吗？
as disassembled atoms in a transporter beam?
我之前从没有听说过此类研究
I have never heard of a study being done.
这是一个吸引人的研究课题
But it would be a fascinating project.
吸引人？
Fascinating?
我们的朋友还在外面，下落不明
Those people are friends of ours out there, if they're still alive.
- 非常正确 - 但是可能性渺茫
- Precisely. - Well, the odds are not good.
- 不，我估计可能性会在400 - 别跟我说这些数据
- No. I would say approximately 400... - Don't quote odds,
也别跟我再说那些不带感情色彩的逻辑，史波克
and don't give me any more dispassionate logic, Mr. Spock.
- 赶快继续寻找他们的下落 - 我对这个建议表示赞同，医生
- Just keep looking for them. - I'd welcome a suggestion, doctor,
虽然你这是感情用事
even an emotional one, as to where to look.
你第一次接受我的意见
The first time you've ever asked me for anything
这可真值得纪念啊
and it has to be an occasion like this.
舰长，进取号会来找我们的，对吧？
Captain, the Enterprise, they will be trying to find us, won't they?
他们会尽力寻找，但是他们能去哪儿找？
They'll be trying. But where do they look?
我们在这，我们也不知道这是哪儿
We're here and we don't know where it is.
这个星系的主星是三元星，缩小了范围
This system's star is a trinary. Limits it a bit.
如果我们和进取号还在同一维度的话
But we're a long way from the Enterprise...
我们恐怕离她的距离也会很远
...if we're even in the same dimension.
我是你的训导员
I am your drill thrall.
- 我的名字叫拉尔斯 - 你想对她怎么样？
- I am called Lars. - What do you want from her?
这不是你该担心的
That is not your concern.
你的训导员一会儿就到
Your drill thralls will attend you presently.
时间不多
There is little time.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
- 出去 - 我被挑选出来训练你的
- Get out. - I have been selected for you.
上尉，你还好吗？
Lieutenant, are you all right?
乌呼拉
Uhura.
上尉？上尉，你还好吗？
Lieutenant? Lieutenant, are you all right?
上尉，回答我！
Lieutenant, answer me!
上尉？发生什么事儿了，乌呼拉上尉？
Lieutenant? What's happening to Lieutenant Uhura?
上尉，你还好吗？
Lieutenant, are you all right?
不允许你拒绝
It is not allowed to refuse selection.
离门远一点儿
Step away from the door.
过来，现在是营养品补给时间
Come. It is the nourishment interval.
舰长日志，星历3259.2
Captain's log, stardate 3259.2.
史波克大副代为指挥
First Officer Spock in command.
舰长，乌呼拉上尉和契科夫少尉
The captain, Lieutenant Uhura, and Ensign Chekov
已经失踪了近2个小时了
have been missing for nearly two hours.
因为数据无效所以电脑推测出的概率也是无效的
Computer probability projections are useless due to insufficient data.
史波克，我在这片氢云里检测到了能量波动
Mr. Spock, I'm getting a fluctuating energy reading on this hydrogen cloud.
信号微弱，长官，但是读数始终超过预估能量水平
It's faint, sir, but it consistently reads an excess of predictable energy level.
有意思
Interesting.
看上去像是一个留下的离子路径
Seems to be an ionization trail.
有什么解释吗，史波克？
What would account for that, Spock?
这也是我正在用电脑分析的问题，医生
Exactly the question I've just fed to the computers, doctor.
结论是
And the answer is...
无法用我们已知的理论进行解释
...nothing known to us would account for it.
传送器无论是从能量上还是范围上都不足以产生这样的影响
The transporter has neither the power nor the range to account for that.
- 设定航线进行追踪，海恩斯少尉 - 是长官
- Plot a follow course, Ensign Haines. - Aye, sir.
就因为你检测到了氢云中的一些异常
You're going to leave here without them
你就打算不管他们，从这儿离开
and run off on some wild-goose chase halfway across the galaxy
然后穿过大半个银河系去追踪行踪不定的一个路径？
just because you found a discrepancy in a hydrogen cloud?
医生，我在对舰长，乌呼拉上尉以及契科夫少尉进行追踪
Doctor, I am chasing the captain, Lieutenant Uhura and Ensign Chekov,
而不是去追踪什么水生家禽，这是目前我们仅有的线索
not some wild aquatic fowl. This is the only lead we've had.
航线设定完成，史波克，航向310，坐标241
Course plotted and laid in, Mr. Spock. Three-10, mark 241.
出发，曲速2
Initiate. Warp factor 2.
你？你是专门为我而选的？
You? You have been selected for me?
不是，我只是你的训练员
No. I am only your drill thrall.
我给你带来了营养品
I have brought you nourishment.
名字挺好听的，契寇
It is a nice name, Chee-koo.
是契科夫
Chekov.
契寇夫，真是个好名字
Chee-koof. It is a very nice name.
我叫塔姆
I am called Tamoon.
很，很高兴认识你，姑娘？
Pleased... Pleased to know you... miss?
你是个非常不错的样品，和其他几个比起来我更喜欢你
You are a fine specimen. I like you better than the others.
我会好好训练你的，这样我的供应者就会把你要走
I will instruct you well, so my Provider will take you.
你可真好，姑娘，但是
That's very kind of you, miss, but...
如果我的供应者被取悦了
If my Provider is pleased,
我们就有可能选中彼此
we may even be selected for each other.
我没意识到我都饿成这样了
I didn't realise I was so hungry.
不管你叫这些什么，吃起来味道不错
Whatever you call this, it was very good.
这些是营养品，这是我们的叫法
It is nourishment. We call it that.
营养品，这个叫法真贴切
Nourishment. That's very practical.
- 你们管这个颈圈叫什么？ - 这是供应者的标识
- What do you call this collar? - It is the sign of our Provider.
用颜色来区分谁是我们的持有者
By the colour of the lights it can be known who holds us.
一旦你被拍出了，你也会有相应的颜色的
When you are vended, you will also have a colour.
拍出？你的意思是拍卖？售卖？
Vended? You mean bought? Sold?
在你展示之后
When you are developed.
出夸路最多的供应者会把他的颜色赐给我们
The Provider who offers the most quatloos puts his colour on us.
我们的种族对这种行为有另外一个叫法:
Our race has another name for it:
奴役
Slavery.
高尔特是唯一一个可以
This collar of obedience...
操控这个控制颈圈的人吗？
...is Galt the only one who can operate it?
这只是为了警告和惩罚
It is only to warn and punish.
- 他是怎么控制的？ - 不允许谈论这个问题
- How does he work it? - It is not permitted to talk of that.
每次都会是你给我提供营养品吗？
Will you provide all my nourishment?
当然，我是你的训练员，我会好好训练你的
Of course. I am your drill thrall. I will train you well.
嗯，我相信你会的
Yes, I'm sure you will.
我必须说，我还从没见过有你这样的军士长呢
I must say, I've never seen a top sergeant who looked like you.
这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是说，你是个漂亮的女人
It means you're a very beautiful woman.
什么是“漂亮”？
What is "beautiful"?
从没有人对你这么说嘛？
You mean nobody's ever told you that before?
漂亮就是
Well, beautiful is...
漂亮
Beautiful...
这就是漂亮
That's beautiful.
莎娜，你是哪儿的人？
Shahna, where were you born?
出生？
Born?
我一直都在这儿
I have been here always.
你的家长，你妈和你爸他们在哪儿？
Your parents, where are they? Your mother and father.
生我的女人死在一场自由式竞技中了
She who bore me was killed in a freestyle match.
- 自由式？ - 你以后会学到的
- Freestyle? - You will learn all these things.
拉尔斯和契科夫的训练员他们不是出生在这儿的
Lars, and Chekov's drill thrall, they weren't born here.
- 他们是从哪儿来的？ - 不允许
- Where do they come from? - It is not permitted...
到了训练时间了
The exercise interval.
这是你的训练专用马甲，穿上
This is your training harness. Put it on.
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
什么都没有，这儿什么都没有
Nothing out there. Nothing out there at all.
我们肯定是进入了一个空旷星域
We certainly seem to be heading into an empty sector.
追溯离子路径
Projecting back along the path of ionization,
最近的星系就是M24的A星
the nearest system is M24 Alpha.
离这里得有24光年那么远呢
That must be two dozen light-years away.
11.630光年
11.630.
你是说他们已经被传送出那么远的距离吗？
Are you suggesting that they could have transported over a distance of?
你这个瓦肯疯子，史波克！
You're out of your Vulcan mind, Spock!
我什么也没说，医生
I am suggesting nothing, doctor.
我仅仅是按照我们仅有的符合逻辑的线索进行追踪而已
I am merely pursuing the only logical course available to us.
停手！
Hold!
这个奴隶没有服从命令
This thrall was slow in obeying a command.
作为对他的惩罚，他将作为你们训练用的靶子
For his punishment, he will be practise target.
击倒这个靶子你们就能够通过训练
As you charge, you will strike the practise target when you pass.
乌呼拉，从你开始
You begin, Uhura.
不
No.
不允许拒绝训练项目
It is not allowed to refuse a training exercise.
我不管你允不允许，我不会这么做的！
I don't care whether it's allowed or not. I will not do it!
我们都不会这么做的，高尔特
None of us will do it, Galt.
这是你们的训练项目
It is part of your training.
这是供应者的要求
The Providers wish it.
- 供应者就是恶棍 - 哥萨克人！
- The devil with the Providers. - Cossacks!
因为你们是新来的，我们才会如此容忍
We have been tolerant because you are newcomers.
但是必须给你们点儿教训
But I see you must be given a lesson.
拉尔斯
Lars.
柯龙
Kloog.
柯龙负责纠正你们的错误
Kloog will administer correction.
乌呼拉，站到指定位置
Uhura, take your place on the Triad.
- 绑上 - 停手
- Tie her. - No.
住手
No.
我为我的手下负责
I'm responsible for the actions of my people.
我要求与供应者会面
I demand to see the Providers.
这不被允许
It is not permitted.
但是，舰长，既然你认为你应该对你的人负责
But, captain, since you assume responsibility for your people,
那么你来接受惩罚
you will take the punishment.
这比颈圈的惩罚舒服多了
It is less painful than the collar.
转过去
Turn around.
舰长，你将作为训练的靶子
Captain, you will be practise target.
就这么损失掉你实在可惜，舰长
It is a shame to lose you, captain,
但是为了杀鸡儆猴也算是值了
but it is worth it as an example to the others.
舰长日志，追加，星历未知
Captain's log, supplemental. Stardate unknown.
我们仍处于被陌生人囚禁的状态
Our strange captivity continues.
这个星球叫三曲星
This planet is called Triskelion.
我么不知道它所处的位置，我们不知道谁在背后控制着它
We do not know its location. We do not know who controls it.
但是显然这里很危险
Its dangers are abundantly clear.
停！
Hold!
休息时间，暂停45秒
Rest interval. Fifteen trisecs.
他挥鞭子的速度太快
He's pretty fast with that whip.
这样的训练会把你变得更强健，喝下去
This will strengthen you. Drink it.
柯龙的左眼是弱点，尽量接近他的左侧
Kloog's left eye is weak. Approach him from that side.
回到场地
Resume places.
停
Hold.
我们停止了，1号供应者
We hold, Provider One.
一号供应者为新来的奴隶出价300夸路
Provider One bids 300 quatloos for the newcomers.
- 2号供应者，350夸路！ - 3号供应者，400夸路！
- Provider Two, 350 quatloos! - Provider Three, 400!
- 一千夸路！ - 一千零五十夸路！
- One thousand quatloos! - One thousand fifty quatloos!
两千
Two thousand.
两千夸路竞价
Two thousand quatloos are bid.
还有人继续追加吗？
Is there a challenge?
新奴隶属于1号供应者
The newcomers have been vended to Provider One.
我们是自由人
We're free people.
我们不属于任何人
We belong to no one.
真够冲的！我出15夸路打赌他驯不熟
Such spirit! I wager 15 quatloos that he is untrainable.
20夸路这仨都是驯不熟的
Twenty quatloos that all three are untrainable.
五千夸路这几个新来的最终结局就是死
Five thousand quatloos that the newcomers will have to be destroyed.
接受，给他们增加标记，高尔特
Accepted. Mark them, Galt.
你们现在的归属非常不错
You now bear the mark of a fine herd.
但是我必须要警告你
But I must warn you, any further disobedience
你现在是完全驯化的的奴隶
now that you are full-fledged thralls
违令者死
will be punishable by death.
史波克，他们被传送到这么远的地方完全讲不通啊
Mr. Spock, it just doesn't make sense they could have come this far.
应该在他们失踪的区域
If there's any chance at all,
尽一切可能的继续搜寻他们
it's to continue to search in the area they were lost.
我们已经对那片区域进行了搜寻
We searched the area.
也有可能我们遗漏了什么
It's always possible to miss something.
比如说传送室机械故障？
Such as a failure in the transporter mechanism?
不，长官，没有出现故障的迹象
No, sir. There was no sign of failure.
是在伽马II星没有出现故障的迹象而已
There was no sign of them in the area of Gamma II.
要是真有的话，那他们
If they weren't there, it's just ridiculous to think
怎么可能还活着，毕竟都过了这么久了
they could still be alive. Not after all this time.
如果是这样，我们只能背水一战，继续目前的航程
In that case, we have nothing to lose by pursuing our present course.
慢点，等等我，等等
Slow down. Slow down. Wait a minute. Wait up.
我们快走了两英里了，能不能喘口气？休息一下
We've covered over two miles. Can we take a breather? A rest.
- 好吧，如果你累了的话 - 好
- Very well, if you are tired. - Yes.
能离开城区真是太好了，哪怕一会儿也好
Well, it's good to get away from that development area, even for a while.
莎娜，为什么供应者们？
Shahna, why do the Providers?
为什么他们喜欢看着其他人受伤死掉？
Why do they like to watch others being hurt, killed?
一直都是这样的
That is the way.
他们的声音听起来很机械
Their voices sound mechanical.
- 他们是计算机吗？ - 计算机？
- Are they computers? - Computers?
你见过他们吗？他们有身体吗？
You've seen them? Do they have bodies?
有是有，但跟我们的不一样
Not such as ours.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
这里被遗弃了
It is not used.
这地方很古老了，有名字吗？
It's very old. Does it have a name?
莎娜…
Shahna...
…这里会不会曾经是供应者的城市？
...could it have been a city for the Providers?
我觉得不应该问这种问题
I do not think it is well to ask such things.
他们有身体的吧，或者曾经有过？
They do have bodies, or did have?
不应该谈论这种事情
One does not talk of such things.
真是美丽的乡村景色啊
Very pretty country.
很像我的故乡，地球
Very much like my home planet, Earth.
- 故乡？ - 我出生的地方
- Planet? - Where I was born.
莎娜，你从不看夜晚的天空吗？
Shahna, don't you ever look at the night sky?
那远方的亮光
The lights up there?
我看过
I have looked at them.
那是恒星
Well, those are stars.
恒星周围有行星
And around them are planets.
那里有人居住，就跟我们一样
And there are people that live on them, just like us.
怎么会有人住在一点亮光上？
How can one live on a flicker of light?
从地球看来，三曲星的三颗恒星，也不过是一点光亮
From Earth, Triskelion's three suns are just a flicker of light.
说实话，这是我见过的最黑暗的星球
Actually, this is the darkest planet I've ever seen.
黑暗？
Dark?
但这里很明亮啊，房间里也很明亮
But all is lighted. Here, the chambers.
奴隶们没有自由，莎娜
The thralls have no freedom, Shahna.
你们什么也不做什么也不想，完全听从供应者的命令
You don't think or do anything but what the Providers tell you.
那还能做什么呢？
What else would one do?
比如说，爱
Love, for one thing.
爱是什么？
What is love?
爱是…
Love...
…是地球上最重要的事
...is the most important thing on Earth,
尤其是男人和女人之间的爱
especially to a man and a woman.
我们也有配偶啊
We, too, have mates.
需要增加群体数量的时候，供应者会为我选配偶
When it is time to increase the herd, my Provider will select one for me.
地球上，我们自己选择配偶
On Earth, we select our own mate.
选一个我们在乎的人
Someone we care for.
在地球上，男人女人生活在一起…
On Earth, men and women live together...
互相扶持，让对方幸福
...help each other, make each other happy.
你怎么能跟我说这些
I do not think your words are allowed.
好吧，好吧
All right. All right.
跟我讲讲供应者们
Tell me about the Providers.
他们是什么样子，生活在哪里
What do they look like? Where do they live?
我从没见过他们，但据说他们跟我们不一样
I have never seen them, but they are said not to be like us.
他们住在…
They stay in...
停下来，快停下来
Stop it. Stop it!
冲我来啊
I'm responsible!
是我让她讲的
I made her talk!
快停下，她快没命了
Stop it! You're killing her!
她什么都没做，是我的错
She did nothing wrong. It was my fault.
你们想找人受罚，冲我来啊
If you want to punish someone, punish me.
求求你了
Please.
这就是你们人类所说的同情心吗？
Is that what you humans call compassion?
很有趣，但是在这里毫无价值
It is interesting, but it has no value here.
你让我们看到了你有趣的一面，舰长
You present many interesting aspects, captain.
但是你必须学会服从，才能成为一名优秀的奴隶
But you must learn obedience. Then you will be an excellent thrall.
好了，没事了，安静下来吧，莎娜
It's all right. It's all right. You can stop crying now, Shahna.
好了没事了
It's all right.
你…你居然冒险承担他们的怒气
You... You risked bringing their anger on yourself.
你为什么这么做？
Why did you do it?
这是我们的传统
It's the custom of my people
帮助遇到困难的人
to help one another when we're in trouble.
那…这…
And... And this...
…这也是“帮助”吗？
...is this also "helping"?
也可以这么说
You could call it that.
那就再帮我一次吧
Please, help me once again.
我从来不知道，两个人之间可以这样
I did not know it could be like this between people.
在你的故乡，一直都是这样吗？
Is it always so in the place you come from?
舰长，你确实让我们吃惊不小啊
Captain, you do indeed present many surprises.
鉴于你取悦了供应者
Because you have amused the Providers,
所以你将不会受到惩罚
there will be no punishment.
回到你的住处吧
Return to your quarters.
史考特先生，能比曲速6再快一点吗？
Mr. Scott, can we manage anything faster than warp 6?
我的意见，长官，我们现在就已经很过分了
It's my opinion that we've gone too far as it is, sir.
他说的没错，史波克
He's right, Spock.
我们在伽马II失去了吉姆和其他人
We've lost Jim and the others back on Gamma II.
你靠着某种疯狂的直觉带着我们逃了这么远…
You've dragged us out here a dozen light-years on some wild hunch that...
医生，我不相信什么直觉
Doctor, I do not respond to hunches.
他们的失踪跟传送室故障没有关系
No transporter malfunction was responsible for the disappearance.
他们当时不在伽马星系中
They were not within the Gamma system.
一道来自三元星系的超高密度聚焦光束
A focused beam of extremely high-intensity light
直直射向了伽马星系
was directed into the Gamma system
我们现在就前往三元星系
from the trinary system we are now approaching.
没有什么目前已知的现象能造成那种光束
No known natural phenomena could have caused that beam.
- 我澄清目前的情况了吗？ - 并没有，史波克先生
- Does that clarify the situation? - No, it doesn't, Mr. Spock.
虽然话说的好听，但你还是在跟着直觉走
It's still a fancy way of saying that you're playing a hunch.
我的直觉告诉我，他们还在伽马II
Well, my hunch is that they're back on Gamma II,
是死是活，都要再搜查一番
dead or alive, and I still want another search.
我跟麦考伊医生的看法一样
Dr. McCoy speaks for me too, sir.
我明白了
I see.
各位，现在我是进取号的指挥官
Gentlemen, I am in command of this vessel,
我们将继续目前的航线
and we shall continue on our present course
除非你们宣布叛变
unless it is your intention to declare a mutiny.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
谁说要叛变了，你这个尖耳朵的老顽固
Who said anything about a mutiny, you stubborn, pointed-eared?
好了，如果在这里找不到他们
All right, if we don't find them here,
那就回到伽马II再搜索一遍，好吗？
will we still have another search on Gamma II?
同意，史考特先生，你能想办法加到曲速7吗？
Agreed. Now, Mr. Scott, could you manage warp 7?
乐意之极，长官，说不定还能再快一点
I'd be more than content to do so, sir. And maybe a wee bit more.
少尉，曲速7
Ensign, warp 7.
今天发生的事让你心烦吗？
You're disturbed about what happened today.
是
Yes.
你让我有一种很奇怪的感觉
You have made me feel strangely.
如果允许，我会问你是不是也这样对其他奴隶？
If it were allowed, I would ask that you have another drill thrall.
我不会那样做的，莎娜
I wouldn't like that, Shahna.
一定不会那样做
I wouldn't like that at all.
对不起，莎娜
I'm sorry, Shahna.
这样可一点都不浪漫
This is going to kill our romance.
- 拉尔斯呢？ - 他去告发我了
- What about Lars? - He's gone to report me.
我跟他说我不喜欢这里的食物
I told him I didn't like the food.
我觉得高尔特是唯一控制这些项圈的人
I think Galt is the only one who controls these collars.
如果能找到我攻击拉尔斯用的相位枪
If we can find the phaser that I threw at Lars,
就能利用其中的电路让这些项圈短路
we can use the circuits to short out these collars.
舰长
Captain.
这只是对你们的警告
Only a reminder.
你们地球人总是这么不寻常，这么不顺服
You Earth people are most unusual, most stimulating.
标准轨道
Standard orbit.
传感器显示这个星球上只有一处生命体聚集地
Sensors indicate only one concentration of life forms on the planet,
就在下半球，类人生物检测
on the lower hemisphere. Humanoid readings.
至少登陆部队有个着手点了
At least that gives our landing force a starting point.
不会派遣登陆部队，医生
There will be no landing force, doctor.
假设舰长和其他人还活着
Assuming the captain and the others are still alive,
派遣大型登陆部队只会让他们的处境更危险
it would be unwise to endanger them by beaming down a large contingent.
那也不能坐视不管啊
We're not going to leave them there while we just sit and wait.
奇怪，没有能量源
Interesting. No power source.
可能被屏蔽了
It may be shielded.
我之前说过，这么做毫无意义
It may be just a wild-goose chase, like we've been telling you.
我应该下去看看，医生
I shall beam down, doctor.
如果和我失去联系，请派遣登陆部队
If I'm unable to communicate, a landing party may be necessary.
史波克先生，如果你要亲自潜入虎穴
Well, Mr. Spock, if you're going into the lion's den,
那应该有医疗官陪伴左右
you'll need a medical officer.
我记得丹尼尔可是独身一人带着信念去冒险的
Daniel, as I recall, had only his faith.
但是欢迎你和我一起，医生
But I welcome your company, doctor.
- 史考特先生，你来指挥 - 是，长官
- Mr. Scott, you'll be in command. - Aye, sir.
史波克先生，你走不了的
No, Mr. Spock. You will not leave the ship.
你们的控制系统已经瘫痪
None of your control systems will operate.
这是怎么回事？
What the devil's going on?
史波克？史波克？
Spock? Spock?
史波克？
Spock!
欢迎来到三曲星，先生们
Welcome to Triskelion, gentlemen.
现在，你们会发现我刚才所言非虚
By now, it must be obvious to you that you have been expected.
他说的是真的，全部都瘫痪了
What the voice said was true, sir. Nothing is functioning.
我非常欣赏各位
Commendations, gentlemen.
在寻找同伴下落时的心思缜密
Your ingenuity in discovering
很明显，你们已经找到了问题的答案
the whereabouts of your companions is noteworthy.
各位，你们听到的声音来自供应者
What you're hearing, gentlemen, is a Provider.
奴隶们称我们为供应者
We are known to the thralls as Providers
因为我们供应他们的一切所需
because we provide for all their needs.
对于他们的智力水平来说，这一术语很容易被理解
The term is easier for their limited mental abilities to comprehend.
供应他们的一切所需，意味着利用
Providing for all their needs means using thralls,
这些自银河系各个星球劫掠来的人们
people stolen from other parts of the galaxy,
让他们互相厮杀，然后供应者投下赌注
to fight each other, and the Providers gamble on the winner.
有意思
Fascinating.
但是供应者们从来不敢现出真身
But these Providers haven't the courage to show themselves.
你们人类总是有很强的好奇心，我们知道
Your species has great curiosity. We knew that.
你们在很多方面都很有趣
You are interesting in many ways.
但是你们会害怕
But you are afraid.
戴着项圈时你们就不会带来危险
You present no danger while you wear the collar.
而只要活着，你们就得戴着项圈
And you wear it as long as you live.
那就现身啊
Then show yourself.
又没有什么妨碍你们的
There is no objection.
能量源被坚硬的岩石保护着
The power source. Shielded by solid rock.
我们在地表以下1000米处
We are 1,000 of your metres beneath the surface.
完全是智力进化的产物
Primary mental evolution.
不可思议
Incredible.
并非如此，舰长
That is not true, captain.
我们也曾是类人形态，但在进化中超越了这一形态
Once we had humanoid form, but we evolved beyond it.
在千万年的进化过程中，专注追求智力的进化
Through aeons of devoting ourselves exclusively to intellectual pursuits,
于是成了你现在所看到的样子
we became the physically simple,
肉体简单，但智力极度发达
mentally superior creature you see before you.
一个奴役其他生物的物种
A species that enslaves other beings
怎能称得上是极度发达呢？
is hardly superior,
无论是否智力超群
mentally or otherwise.
奴隶在我们的游戏规则中必不可少
The thralls are necessary to the games.
体育竞技是我们唯一的挑战
We have found athletic competitions our only challenge,
我们存在的唯一目的
the only thing which furnishes us with purpose.
但这没有任何意义，对你们的智力发展来说毫无用处
It's an unproductive purpose, unworthy of your intellect.
我们只使用低等生物
We use only inferior beings.
我们认为，银河系中的所有生物形式
We have found that all life forms in the galaxy
都具备高级进化的能力
are capable of superior development.
也许你们进化的程度并不如自己所想的那么高级
Perhaps you're not as evolved as you believe.
你的推测很有趣，舰长
An interesting speculation, captain.
你，还有你的族人都颇具挑战性
You and your people are most challenging.
没错，颇具挑战性
Yes, most challenging.
我们也希望这样的新血液能刺激我们的奴隶群
It was hoped that such new blood would stimulate our stock of thralls.
但不幸的是，你们必须灭亡
How unfortunate that you must be destroyed.
我们若是灭亡，你们也将尸骨无存
Our destruction will result only in your own.
你们或许能控制进取号
You may control the Enterprise,
但绝不可能匹敌整个星际联邦的力量
but you cannot match the force of the entire Federation.
你们的星舰会在一场电磁风暴中飞灰湮灭
Your ship will be destroyed by a magnetic storm.
不可能与你们的基地取得任何联系
No communications with your base will be possible.
对你的族人来说，你们的命运将成为千古之谜
Your fate will remain a mystery to your people.
你们居然胆敢称自己是极度发达
And you call yourselves superior!
你们只是丧失灵魂的谋杀犯 肆意夺取他人的性命并以此为赌注
You're murderers without the spirit to really wager for the lives you take!
赌注？请解释一下，舰长
Wager? Explain yourself, captain.
我的族人是宇宙中最伟大
My people pride themselves
最成功的赌徒，并因此而感到自豪
on being the greatest, most successful gamblers in the universe.
我们会为了任何东西竞争，权力，名气，女人
We compete for everything: Power, fame, women.
任何我们渴望得到的东西
Everything we desire.
想要赢是我们的本性
And it is our nature to win.
若是不信，你可以看看我们对银河系的探索
For proof, I offer you our exploration of this galaxy.
我们了解你们的竞争能力，舰长
We are aware of your competitive abilities, captain.
那么…
Well, then...
…我打赌…
...I wager...
…由你们来挑选武器
...that with weapons of your own choice,
就在这里，就现在
right here and now,
我的人可以打赢相同数量的你方奴隶
my people can overcome an equal number of thralls set against us.
100夸路，赌新来的赢
A hundred quatloos on the newcomers.
400夸路，赌新来的输
Four hundred quatloos against the newcomers.
200夸路，赌新来的输
Two hundred quatloos against!
500夸路，赌新来的赢，采用多轮淘汰法
Five hundred for the newcomers. Contest by multiple elimination.
等等，等等，听我说
Wait! Wait! Hear me.
我们不会为了夸路这种无关紧要的东西打赌
We can't wager for trifles like quatloos.
赌注要更高才行
The stakes must be higher.
说说你想要什么赌注，舰长
Name your stakes, captain.
如果我们赢了，让进取号和我的船员安全地离开这里
If we win, the Enterprise and its crew leaves here in safety.
而且，释放这里的所有奴隶
Furthermore, all the thralls on the planet must be freed.
自治吗？他们会饿死的
Anarchy. They would starve.
你们要教他们如何
You will educate and train them
建立起正常的自治文明
to establish a normal self-governing culture.
让奴隶自治？简直荒唐！
Thralls govern themselves? Ridiculous!
这件事我们在银河系的许多星球都实施成功过
We have done the same with cultures throughout the galaxy.
难道你们愿意承认自己不如我们？
Are you willing to admit that we can do something you can't?
- 没什么是我们做不到的 - 你要是输了呢，舰长？
- There is nothing we cannot do. - And if you lose, captain?
如果我们输了？
If we lose?
我们就留在这里，进取号的全部船员
We will remain here. The entire crew of the Enterprise.
宇宙中最顽固，最意志坚定的竞争者
The most stubborn, determined competitors in the universe.
我们将成为你们的奴隶，遵守你们的游戏规则
We'll become thralls, enter your games,
服从你们的命令，绝不造反
obey your orders without rebellion.
可以保证你们将体验到数代
You'll be assured of generations
最最精彩的竞技和赌注
of the most exciting wagering you've ever had.
你提出的赌注的确很高，舰长
Your stakes are indeed high, captain.
对真正的赌徒来说不算高
Not for true gamesters.
我们接受你的赌注，不过有一个条件
We will accept your stakes on one condition.
说吧
Name it.
作为舰长，你的意志看来最为坚定
As leader of your people, your spirit seems most indomitable.
我们提议，你单独一人对抗我们所选的三人
We suggest you, alone, pitted against three contestants of our choosing.
三对一？
Three against one?
这赔率的确很高
Those are pretty high odds.
对于真正的赌徒来说就不算，舰长
Not for true gamesters, captain.
这样不公平
Your terms are unfair.
正相反，这条件非常公平
On the contrary, they're extremely fair.
因为你还可以选择死亡
Since your alternative is death.
这样的话，我接受你们的条件
Well, in that case, I'll accept your terms.
高尔特会为你做准备
Galt will prepare you.
既然你这么做是为了你的船员
Because you wager your skill for all your people,
那么他们将会看到比赛的结果
they will be permitted to watch the outcome of the game
就在进取号的屏幕上
on the ship's viewscreen.
- 史波克先生，快看 - 舰长，你要自卫
- Mr. Spock, look. - Captain, you will defend.
奴隶应待在蓝色区域，你待在黄色区域
Thralls must stay in the blue area. You will take the yellow.
若踏入对方区域，违规者就会失去一件武器
Touching an opposing colour deprives a contestant of one weapon.
若杀掉对手，则被杀的选手退出
An opponent must be killed to be removed from the game.
若只是受伤，则由新选手取代
If only wounded, he is replaced by a fresh thrall.
清楚了吗，舰长
Is that clear, captain?
清楚了
Yes, that's clear.
上帝啊，这是要干什么？
What in the name of heaven is this?
这跟上帝没关系
Heaven's got very little to do with this.
莎娜
Shahna.
你撒谎了
You lied.
你说的都是谎话
Everything you said.
奴隶投降
The thralls surrender!
你赢了，寇克舰长，很不幸
You have won, Captain Kirk, unfortunately.
然而，赌注条件的神圣性不容侵犯
However, the terms of the wager will be honoured.
你们自由了
You are free.
去掉项圈吧
Remove your collars.
你们会教奴隶学会自治吗？
The thralls will be trained?
必然，这是我们承诺过的
They will be trained. We have said it.
你们会发现，这个游戏比起你们
I think you'll find it a much more exciting game
之前玩的，要有意思多了
than the one you've been playing.
对不起，莎娜，我没有骗你
I'm sorry, Shahna. I didn't lie.
我不得不那么做
I did what was necessary.
- 希望有一天你能明白 - 我明白，一点点
- Someday I hope you'll understand. - I understand. A little.
你要离开了吗？
You will leave us now?
是
Yeah.
回到天空中的亮光中去么
To go back to the lights in the sky?
是的
Yes.
我愿意跟你一起去
I would like to go to those lights with you.
- 带上我吧 - 不行的
- Take me. - I can't.
那就教会我，我会随你去
Then teach me how, and I will follow you.
你有太多东西要先在这里学习
There is so much you must learn here first.
供应者会教你们，用心学习吧，莎娜
The Providers will teach you. Learn it, Shahna.
你的族人必须先学习，然后才能触摸到星星
All your people must learn before you can reach for the stars.
莎娜
Shahna.
- 史考特 - 是，舰长
- Scotty. - Aye, sir.
传我们回舰
Beam us up.
再见了，吉姆·寇克
Goodbye, Jim Kirk.
我会学习…
I will learn...
…看着天空的亮光…
...and watch the lights in the sky...
…想起你
...and remember.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/